{"_id": "f8866c5e", "question": "Can stem cells help with stroke recovery?", "answers": "Responding to A2A.\nThere are a lot of factors: different types of stem cells; different kinds of strokes; when would the stem cells be administered?\nAll those factors noted, it seems promising, and research IS ongoing:\nStem Cell Therapy for Stroke Recovery\nNewest treatments get stroke victims recovering faster. Combining those with stem cells is even better. Learn more about the latest treatments offered at the University of Miami Health System.\nhttps://umiamihealth.org/en/treatments-and-services/cardiovascular/stem-cell-therapy-for-stroke-recovery\nStroke Fact Sheet\nCIRM funds many projects seeking to better understand stroke and to translate those discoveries into new therapies. Description In the U.S., almost 800,000 people have a stroke each year and more than 140,000 people die of their stroke. It is the leading cause of serious, long-term disability in the U.S.\nhttps://www.cirm.ca.gov/our-progress/disease-information/stroke-fact-sheet\nLooking at one meta-analysis, in this case for ischemic stroke:\n“Our review shows that stem cell-based therapies can improve the neurological deficits and activities of daily living in patients with ischemic stroke.”\nStem cell-based therapies for ischemic stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials\nRecently, extensive researches about stem cell-based therapies for ischemic stroke have been published; our review evaluated the efficacy and safety of stem cell-based therapies for ischemic stroke. Our review was registered on PROSPERO (http://www.crd.york.ac.uk/PROSPERO), registration number CRD42019135805. Two independent observers searched PubMed, EMBASE, Cochrane Library (Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials), and Web of Science (Science Citation Index Expanded) for relevant studies up to 31 May 2019. We included clinical trials which compared efficacy outcomes (measured by National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS), modified Rankin scale (mRS), or Barthel index (BI)) and safety outcomes (such as death and adverse effects) between the stem cell-based therapies and control in ischemic stroke. We performed random effect meta-analysis using Review Manager 5.3. Our review included nine randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and seven non-randomized studies (NRSs), involving 740 participants. Stem cell-based therapies were associated with better outcomes measured by NIHSS (mean difference (MD) − 1.63, 95% confidence intervals (CI) − 2.73 to − 0.53, I2 =60%) and BI (MD 14.68, 95% CI 1.12 to 28.24, I2 = 68%) in RCTs, and by BI (MD 6.40, 95% CI 3.14 to 9.65, I2 = 0%) in NRSs. However, the risk of bias was high and the efficacy outcomes of RCTs were high heterogeneity. There was no significant difference in mortality between the stem cell group and the control group. Fever, headache, and recurrent stroke were the most frequently reported adverse effects. Our review shows that stem cell-based therapies can improve the neurological deficits and activities of daily living in patients with ischemic stroke.\nhttps://stemcellres.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13287-020-01762-z\nCan’t copy pertinent sections from here, but this is interesting:\nSteinberg Lab Research: Stem Cells\nSTEM CELL THERAPY offers enormous promise for the majority of the 795,000 Americans yearly who suffer a stroke yet currently have no pharmacological therapy to promote recovery. Preclinical data from our lab and others have demonstrated that stem cell transplantation can enhance stroke recovery. This has led to major efforts to advance stem cell therapy for stroke to the clinic, including our human neural stem cell (hNSC) product, NR1 cells, which is transitioning to the clinic via a California Institute for Regenerative Medicine (CIRM)-funded Disease Team program . Understanding how hNSCs interact with the stroke-injured brain to induce recovery is crucial to maximizing their effectiveness. Once we understand the mechanisms by which transplanted hNSCs exert therapeutic effects, we can exploit their full clinical potential as well as predict and prevent potential side effects. Consequently, we are studying optimal parameters for successful transplantation strategies in rodent models of stroke; these parameters will depend on the cross talk between the graft and the host and will facilitate understanding of the mechanisms underlying cell-enhanced functional recovery. Stroke damage encompasses a wide range of pathologies. The initial vascular damage of stroke triggers a cascade of damaging events that occur days after the initial infarct. The unique advantage of using stem cells for post-stroke recovery lies in the multiple modalities through which they enhance recovery. Our current paradigm is that hNSCs transplanted into the host stroke brain, rather than exerting their effects directly by replacing damaged tissue, secrete factors and interact with the stroke milieu in a manner that stimulates endogenous repair mechanisms that are activated by stroke.\nhttps://med.stanford.edu/steinberg-lab/research/stemcells.html\nTo be blunt, IF we had sane health insurance (See Comprehensive, Constitutional Health Care 2020—Facebook page, group, book), we’d be investigating things like this. It is possible to do legit stem cells for not that huge of a cost and if you can get the body to HEAL instead of playing with bits and pieces of “management” with BigPharma meds, the long costs for rehab, the lost productivity (stroke victim can’t work in many cases; sometimes a family member must take off to care for him…), people would see that something that clearly has merit IS worth trying to help people return to health. Will it work well for everyone? No. Nothing done now does either. Have to run risk/benefit ratio of the big picture which includes quality of life. Under the CCHC plan would NOT be unfair to anyone about costs either.)\nWe really do need to get the death grip special interests have on medicine OUT of the picture. Legit profit by those with NO medical skills is OK because there IS a business aspect to medicine, but BIR costs are 30% of health care costs and doctors and their staff have their time wasted on BS while hoops are jumped through. We are SO ready for a LOGICAL system.\nWould encourage you to reach out to neurologists who are open to stem cells and see what options exist for your loved one. This is NOT “woo-woo” and stroke is too serious and too common to NOT get more attention.\nBTW, about PREVENTION of strokes. Absolutely stroke risk is higher for folks with insulin/glucose issues, Vitamin D deficiency, gut health are also tied in. Pinned post here is pertinent:\nL.M.'s Random Thoughts\nInsulin resistance and risk for stroke\nBackground and purpose: Resistance to insulin-mediated glucose uptake by peripheral tissues is a cardinal defect in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Insulin resistance is also common among nondiabetic individuals, and may be an important risk factor for stroke in both populations. The authors review the definition, epidemiology, and treatment of insulin resistance. Methods: The authors searched Medline (1977–2001) and reviewed bibliographies to identify pertinent English-language publications. Results: Insulin resistance is present in most patients with type 2 diabetes. It is also common among elderly persons, certain ethnic groups, and persons with hypertension, obesity, physical deconditioning, and vascular disease. The principal pathophysiologic defect is impaired intracellular signaling in muscle tissue leading to defective glycogen synthesis. Insulin resistance is associated with numerous metabolic, hematologic, and cellular events that promote atherosclerosis and coagulation. The association between insulin resistance and risk for stroke has been examined in four case-control studies and five prospective observational cohort studies. Six of the nine studies are methodologically sound and provide evidence that insulin resistance is associated with risk for stroke. Conclusion: Insulin resistance may be a prevalent risk factor for stroke. New drugs can safely reduce insulin resistance and may have a role in stroke prevention.\nhttps://n.neurology.org/content/59/6/809\nVitamin D and stroke: promise for prevention and better outcome - PubMed\nThe role of vitamin D (VitD) has recently been expanded beyond bone homeostasis and regulation of calcium levels. VitD deficiency has been proposed as a new risk factor for cardiovascular disease, including stroke. Low 25(OH)VitD levels are very common among post-stroke patients, probably due to the …\nhttps://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22724468/\nGut Microbiota and Stroke\nIschemic stroke remains a significant health problem, which is expected to increase owing to an aging population. A considerable proportion of stroke patients suffer from gastrointestinal complications, including dysphagia, gastrointestinal hemorrhage, ...\nhttps://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7061503/"}
{"_id": "7acf3ec2", "question": "What are the best strategies for stroke recovery?", "answers": "Emergency treatment of stroke\nStroke\ntreatment\nshould be done as soon as possible. When the brain vessel is blocked, damage to the brain tissue begins to occur. This damage expands as you wait. When the clogged vessel\nis large and the time is longer brain damage increases.\nOpening the vein as soon as possible prevents all of them from expanding the damage to the brain tissue. In the brain tissue, the less restricted the damage caused by the stroke, the sooner and faster we can recover. Therefore, rapid treatment means early and quick recovery when it comes to stroke.\nIntravascular clot-dissolving drug treatment (Thrombolysis)\nIt is the intravascular clot-dissolving drug application that can be performed within the first 4.5 hours at the latest after stroke symptoms begin. Its ideal is to do it as soon as possible. This treatment dissolves the clot and helps the blood flow to recover quickly and effectively, thereby improving the stroke.\nIf the patient's condition is not suitable for the application of this treatment or if the period since the occurrence of stroke has been prolonged, intravenous anticoagulant therapy cannot be performed. Your doctor will resort to other medications and methods in treatment.\nAngiographic clot removal treatment (Thrombectomy\n)\nIf the main vessels feeding the brain are clogged with a clot, clot-dissolving medication, intravenous thrombolysis, which is applied through a vein, is not sufficient to dissolve the clot mass in these large vessels. In this case, the primary purpose of the treatment is to find the brain vessel clogged with angio method and remove the clot with select devices. The 'angiographic clot removal treatment' applied in the first 6 hours is so useful that 1 out of 3 patients who are treated ultimately return to their former lives.\nOne of these two treatment applications is not used as an alternative to the other. On the contrary, it is used as complementary and success enhancing."}
{"_id": "512a82f6", "question": "What are some techniques or medicines for stroke recovery?", "answers": "Sadly the cances for a full recovery after a stroke are quite low, especially when the person is old and the brain isn't as flexible as in younger years.\nBut there are some new techniques like tDCS (which sends a current through the brain to stimulate it) and TMS (uses magnetic fields so stimulate the brain). These techniques are quite new and are mostly in experimental states and thus not avaliable for the public.\nYou also have to consider the effects/risks of the threatments (which are not known yet or are in clinical study) and also if the effect is worth the effort. Your grand-dad made a good recovery, is it really worth to take several trips to the hospital just for a new threatment with unknown results ?"}
{"_id": "eff3c58b", "question": "This post says that time is important for stroke recovery. Do you think is there any golden time for faster stroke recovery?", "answers": "For a tPA injection yes, if a clot interrupts blood flow to the brain it needs to be administered within 3 hours to minimize the effects of the loss of blood supply. Otherwise, for rehab, victims of a stroke have been done a disservice for years. They are told that the fastest recovery of lost abilities comes in the first 3–4 months and that further improvement after 1 year is unlikely. This is not true. What is true is that spontaneous recovery after 1 year is unusual. However, with specific Occupational, Physical and Speech therapies for CVA an improvement can take place at any time. I have worked with people whose stroke was 5 years prior and have seen dramatic improvements in strength, movement, gait and balance. So, no I don’t believe there is a golden time."}
{"_id": "1e26d5ae", "question": "What are the brain stroke recovery options after 7 years?", "answers": "India - Hyperbaric Oxygen chamber can boost brain repair years after stroke or trauma:\nThrough the use of hyperbaric oxygen therapy, medical researchers have found a way to restore a significant amount of neurological function in brain tissue thought to be chronically damaged by stroke, traumatic injury, and metabolic disorder -- even years after the original injury.\nStroke, traumatic injury, and metabolic disorder are major causes of brain damage and permanent disabilities, including motor dysfunction, psychological disorders, memory loss, and more. Current therapy and rehab programs aim to help patients heal, but they often have limited success.\nThe tenfold increase in oxygen levels during HBOT treatment supplies the necessary energy for rebuilding neuronal connections and stimulating inactive neurons to facilitate the healing process, explains Dr. Efrati…..\nKindly click on the link below to read more:\nhttps://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/01/130123144218.htm\nJournal Reference:\n• Shai Efrati, Gregori Fishlev, Yair Bechor, Olga Volkov, Jacob Bergan, Kostantin Kliakhandler, Izhak Kamiager, Nachum Gal, Mony Friedman, Eshel Ben-Jacob, Haim Golan. Hyperbaric Oxygen Induces Late Neuroplasticity in Post Stroke Patients - Randomized, Prospective Trial. PLoS ONE, 2013; 8 (1): e53716 DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0053716\nhttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4wa5Sjm_Nyo\nkindly visit: India. Affordable Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy Chamber in\nStroke\nRehabilitation for\nStroke\nSurvivors."}
{"_id": "69b392fa", "question": "What type of physiotherapy is best for stroke recovery?", "answers": "Anything that gets the blood moving. Sorry I'm not specific, but a stroke can range from being very severe n debilitating to mild n u can get around.\nIf you are asking for yourself, I'm going to suggest a low-impact class like yoga or tai chi. They work on balance, stretching,n strength conditioning. Yoga can be done in a wheelchair. I used to have a video called \"Chair Yoga.\"\nIf you are a caregiver, this might be too high. Ask the consumer's doctor for a referral to Physical Therapy for YOU to be taught Range of Motion exercises. YOU do these on the consumer, because he or she can't. This is usually forgotten at discharge because the patient doesn't immediately show signs of stiffening.\nMore can then be done with a total care patient, but they have to be kept functional.\nYou are going to have to go in n get a referral to be seen. To most this means u have medical Insurance. I’m concerned about the very mild with no insurance. Computer access is easy n ppl try to self-diagnose. For those, enroll in low-cost Parks & Rec n city or college run classes n don’t let anything freeze up. The problems are too various.\nIt can be done with nothing- no fancy rehab or therapy. The following is a true story. At that time, n maybe even now, Mexico did not have a rehab program. Intensive Brain Remaking.\nThis man got lucky. His son is a doctor. He wasn’t completely on his own."}
{"_id": "e284098d", "question": "How does neurorehabilitation help with stroke recovery?", "answers": "A stroke happens when a vein in the cerebrum breaks and drains, or when there's a blockage in the blood supply to the brain. The break or blockage keeps blood and oxygen from arriving at the cerebrum's tissues.\nWithout oxygen, synapses and tissue become damaged and start to die within no time. The loss of blood flow to the brain harms tissues inside the cerebrum. Manifestations of a stroke appear in the body parts constrained by the injured part of the brain. The sooner an individual having a stroke gets care, the better their result is probably going to be. Therefore, it's useful to know the indications of a stroke so you can act rapidly.\nStroke manifestations can include:\n1. Paralysis\n2. Numbness or shortcoming in the arm, face, and leg, particularly on one side of the body\n3. Trouble talking or getting discourse\n4. Confusion\n5. Slurring discourse\n6. Vision issues, for example, inconvenience finding in one or the two eyes with vision darkened or obscured, or twofold vision\n7. Trouble strolling\n8. Loss of parity or coordination\n9. Dizziness\n10. Severe, unexpected migraine with an obscure reason\nStroke requires immediate medical emergency handling. If you think you or someone else is having a stroke, call the hospital immediately. Prompt treatment is key to preventing the following outcomes:\nBrain damage\nLong-term disability\nDeath\nTypes of stroke:\nStrokes fall into three primary classifications: transient ischemic assault (TIA), ischemic stroke, and hemorrhagic stroke. These classifications are additionally separated into different kinds of strokes, including:\nA. Embolic stroke\nB. Thrombotic stroke\nC. Intracerebral stroke\nD. Subarachnoid stroke\nThe sort of stroke you have influenced your treatment and recovery process.\nCause of stroke:\nThe reason for a stroke relies upon the sort of stroke. The three primary sorts of stroke are transient ischemic assault (TIA), ischemic stroke, and hemorrhagic stroke.\nA TIA is brought about by a transitory blockage in an artery that prompts the cerebrum. The blockage, normally blood coagulation, prevents blood from streaming to a specific part of the brain. A TIA ordinarily goes on for a couple of moments up to a couple of hours, and afterward, the blockage moves and bloodstream is reestablished.\nLike a TIA, an ischemic stroke is brought about by a blockage in a supply route that prompts the brain. This blockage might be blood coagulation, or it might be brought about by atherosclerosis. With this condition, plaque (a greasy substance) develops on the walls of the blood vessels. A bit of the plaque can break off and stop in a vein, hindering the progression of blood and causing an ischemic stroke.\nA hemorrhagic stroke, then again, is brought about by a burst or spilling vein. Blood saturates or around the tissues of the cerebrum, causing pressure and damaging brain cells.\nStroke treatment:\nProper medical treatment and prompt treatment are important to recovering from a stroke. It is said that “Time lost is brain lost.” Call your nearby hospital as soon as you realize you may be having a stroke, or if you suspect that someone is having a stroke.\nTreatment for stroke depends on the type of stroke:\nIschemic stroke and TIA\nThese stroke types are caused by a blood clot or other blockage in the brain. For that reason, they’re largely treated with similar techniques, which include:\n• Antiplatelet and anticoagulants\n• Clot-breaking drugs\n• One such medication, tissue plasminogen activator (tPA), or Alteplase IV r-tPA, is viewed as the most significant medication in ischemic stroke treatment. It works by dissolving blood clusters rapidly, whenever conveyed inside the initial 3 to 4.5 hours after indications of your stroke started. Individuals who get a tPA infusion are bound to recover from a stroke, and less inclined to have any enduring handicap because of the stroke.\n• Mechanical thrombectomy\n• Stents\n• Surgery\nHemorrhagic stroke:\nStrokes caused by bleeds or leaks in the brain require different treatment strategies. Treatments for hemorrhagic stroke include:\n• Medications\nNot at all like with an ischemic stroke, in case you're having a hemorrhagic stroke, the treatment objective is to make your blood coagulation. Consequently, you might be offered drugs to neutralize any blood thinners you take.\nYou may likewise be recommended drugs that can reduce blood pressure, lower the pressure in your brain, prevent seizures, and prevent blood vessel constriction.\n• Coiling\n• Clamping\n• Surgery\nIn addition to emergency treatment, doctors will advise you on discharge on how to prevent future strokes.\nPost-discharge one of the important which helps in recovering the disability is neurorehabilitation.\nNeurorehabilitation is a combination of multiple therapies, it takes the help of occupational therapy and physiotherapy with patients and their families to build back the functions and movements of people affected by hemiparetic stroke. The main goal is to get their skills to work at the maximum level, so patients can rebuild self-esteem and a positive attitude towards life. Recovering from a stroke can be a long, almost hopeless process, but with the new adaption skills patients learn, they become empowered and gain the ability for community reintegration.\nNeurorehabilitation therapies educate or retrain patients on how to improve or recover their communication and mobility skills, as well as other aspects of their daily lives. In its treatments, neurorehabilitation focuses on the psychological, creative, and nutritional elements of each and every patient's recovery.\nNeurorehabilitation should be:-\nHolistic approach:\nProvide not only physical and cognitive recovery, but also include psychological, social, and cultural aspects of the patient’s personality and those of their family.\nPatient-focused:\nHealth-care strategies customized to the requirement of the patient and their family.\nInclusive:\nDeveloped and implemented by multidisciplinary teams of qualified and motivated therapists or doctors experienced in similar types of collaboration.\nParticipatory:\nPatients and families are actively involved and build a trusting relationship, work together with the team of medical professionals.\nSaving:\nHelp the patient amplify autonomy and decrease physical disability, reliance on portability helps.\nLifelong:\nSupports and follow-up carried out from injury onset to the highest possible level of recovery of function, even later in life.\nResolving:\nInclude adequate resources for efficiently attending to each patient’s difficulties as they arise.\nCommunity-focused:\nDiscover arrangements that best fit parts of the network and make assets that help the patient in social reintegration.\nKey Points of Successful Rehabilitation:\nIt’s important that patients understand their progress during rehabilitation depends on:\n• Starting of rehabilitation on time regarding the therapeutic window\n• The severity and area of the brain injury\n• Their own attitudes and behavior (daily commitment to exercise)\n• The rehabilitation team’s skill and experience\n• The cooperation of family and practitioners or therapist\n• Successful activation of secondary areas\n• Successful activation of contralateral areas\nStroke neurorehabilitation is a progressive and dynamic procedure planned for empowering patients to come to their ideal physical, intellectual, passionate, informative, and socially useful levels.\nThis strategy for treatment offers various activities to assist patients recover lost motor functions and reduce damage brought about by a stroke. Neurorehabilitation likewise offers deep-rooted help required by patients and their families as they rejoin a network. It permits roused patients to arrive at their definitive objectives of recovering freedom and coming back to typical life."}
{"_id": "03e62fb2", "question": "What are useful pranayam & asan for mini stroke recovery and healing leg muscle stiffness due to a stroke?", "answers": "Stroke is also called CVA - cerebrovascular accident.\nIt is a damage of the brain due to interruption of it blood vessels.\nSymptoms include difficult in walking,speaking or undersatnding. Also numbness of face, arm or leg.\nIt is a medical emergency.\nOnce medical treatment is on and conditions under control yogasan and pranayam should be pressed into to improve the inner strenth and immunity.\nPranayam course should be followed first. All the types of pranayaams be adopted one after another based on the improvement in the condition.\nHigh blood pressure is the foremost cause of strokes. Meaning we should start with the ine pranayam type which balance Blood pressure immediately and purifies the nurological network of the body.\n‘ANULOM VILOM' performs both the requirment - normalising high blood pressure and purification of nerves\nSo follow the following order of pranayam: a) anulom vilom ( nadi shodhan ) pranayam. b) kapal bhati,c) bhramari, bhastika and rest be followed after considerable improvement after doctors cosultations.\nNow yogasana can be pressed into.\nHOW TO DO ANULOM VELOM ( NADI SHIDHAN) PRANAYAM:\nIdeally it should be performed while sitiing , spine straight. But under the cinditions patient can di it while laying in bed.\nRelax the body and mind as much as possible. Close the right nasal with right hand thumb . Inhale ( just breath in with force you usually inhale) .\nNow close left nasal and exhale to with same force ( normal).\nPress left nasal and inhale with right nasal ; switch to right nasal ,exhale with left nasal.\nThis is one cycle. Repeat the cycle for 5 times to increase it gradually with improvement .\nOnce patient starts feeling at ease and shows interest increase the force of breath little and also length of breath.\nThis way gradually perform anulom vilom. THIS ALONE HAS CAPACITY TO RECOVER TO THE MOST.\nYOGASANA: post stroke 'sookchhama yogasana' ( micro yogas) are advised. Based on the effected parts.\nADVICE:. In addition to pranayam and yogasana soft massage if 'clove Oil' in effected parts is advisable."}
{"_id": "67aaa65a", "question": "Can targeting gut microbes help stroke recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a22c9b2d", "question": "Can a laptop increase stroke recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f4093fad", "question": "Is the Cuban medical system really that good, in particular for rehabilitation for things like post stroke recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "79de50ee", "question": "Has anyone experienced transcranial stimulation for stroke recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8ce7df7d", "question": "Where can I find information on the benefits of Massage Therapy for stroke recovery?", "answers": "I use Stroke\nEngine -\nStroke\nRehabilitation Information for Clinicians and Families -\nStroke\nto check validity of interventions and don't find anything for massage. I still believe in it because Margaret Yekutiel in her book, 'Sensory Re-Education of the Hand After Stroke' suggests than improved sensation leads to better motor recovery"}
{"_id": "7dba7513", "question": "How well does the stroke recovery smart hand glove work?", "answers": "I didn’t use a smart glove, but I did use a robotic exoskeleton when I was learning to walk again. It helped quite a bit.\nI still do the “Ekso walk” which is a slightly exaggerated walk, with each phase of the stepping and weight shifting process emphasized. I do it simply to make sure I don’t lapse into bad habits. It makes me focus on what I’m doing, not letting the affected leg drag, making sure to flex my foot to strike with the heel first, etc."}
{"_id": "0212a03e", "question": "How reliable is Acupuncture? I heard acupuncture is good for stroke recovery patients. Is that true?", "answers": "True. Generally speaking, it is reliable for stroke recovery. It will be better if you can combine different methods: acupuncture, Chinese herbs, modern medicine, etc; that way it will get better faster."}
{"_id": "8e468033", "question": "Do you think the Brunnstrom stages is still valid on stroke recovery?", "answers": "Not with descriptions like this…\nA patient can plateau at any of these stages, but will generally follow this sequence if he or she makes a full recovery.[1]\n[2]\nBrunnstrom Approach - Wikipedia\nWhen talking about hemiplegia (paralyzed limbs) and hemiparesis (weak limbs). “Full recovery” isn’t possible, there will be residual effects even with those with hemiparesis."}
{"_id": "034821fa", "question": "What recommendations do you have for long term stroke recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0e414fe4", "question": "How can augmented video game help in stroke recovery as scientist claims?", "answers": "To understand this, let us look at few things.\nWhat is stroke:[1] When blood flow to an area of the brain is cut off then brain cells in that part of the brain don’t get oxygen and they begin to die. Depending on what part of the brain it is, the patient may experience loss in that function like memory or muscle movement.\n[2]\nWhat is required by stroke patients to recover: Depending on how severe the stroke is and what part of the brain is affected, the patient might experience difficult in moving arms and legs. In case of minor strokes, the patients recover completely. They normally have to go through physiotherapy by a trained physiotherapist. The problem is that in many cases, there aren’t enough qualified physiotherapist needed for helping patients recover.\n[3]\nAugmented Video Games: Augmented video games provide virtual reality and proper game program can provide physical exercise for the same muscle groups as is given by a physiotherapist. It can even be tracked and monitored as it is all done by a computer.\n[4]\nThis is how augmented video games help with stroke recovery.\nThanks for A2A.\nFootnotes\n[1] National Stroke Association\n[2] Image on stroke.org\n[3] Image on basildonandthurrock.nhs.uk\n[4] Image on cloudfront.net"}
{"_id": "f19d7c2c", "question": "What role does physical therapy play in stroke recovery?", "answers": "Firstly..The types and degrees of disability that follow a stroke depend upon which area of the brain is damaged. Generally, stroke can cause five types of disabilities: paralysis or problems controlling movement; sensory disturbances including pain; problems using or understanding language; problems with thinking and memory; and emotional disturbances.So physical therapy is very important to these people to become able and independent alsoRehabilitation helps stroke survivors relearn skills that are lost when part of the brain is damaged. For example, these skills can include coordinating leg movements in order to walk or carrying out the steps involved in any complex activity. Rehabilitation also teaches survivors new ways of performing tasks to circumvent or compensate for any residual disabilities. Individuals may need to learn how to bathe and dress using only one hand, or how to communicate effectively when their ability to use language has been compromised. There is a strong consensus among rehabilitation experts that the most important element in any rehabilitation program is carefully directed,well-focused, repetitive practice—the same kind of practice used by all people when they learn a new skill, such as playing the piano or pitching a baseball."}
{"_id": "43a1e297", "question": "Do you think this blog is a helpful guide for fast stroke recovery?", "answers": "Medical professionals such as doctors, nurses, and therapists can make only an educated guess of how a person will recover based on the location and severity of the stroke.\nIt seems to me that the location and severity of the stroke determines what functions are most likely to be affected. That can guide doctors, nurses and therapists as to the types of post-stroke rehabilitation the person may need.\nHow well an individual recovers is mostly determined by how diligently they participate in the rehab activities and exercises. I’ve seen people, who had terrible functional losses from the stroke, recover so well that if I hadn’t known they’d had a stroke, I never would have guessed.\nSpeech is one of those areas. People who give up, thinking it is hopeless and the speech therapy exercises are stupid don’t recover very well. Those who keep working at it on their own as well as with therapists recover much better.\nThe stroke may cause a weakness or paralysis on your body. You should focus on regaining these weakened muscles, so you can get back to your daily activities independently.\nHemiparesis, one sided weakness, is not initially from loss of muscle. Immediately after the stroke, the person may be paralyzed on one side, but with intensive rehab they can regain movement within weeks. Their muscles are probably still as strong as they were before the stroke, but the new neural pathways are not strong. Control over the muscles is weak, not the muscles themselves.\nThe stroke survivor should focus on using the hemiparetic side as much as possible to maintain their muscle strength and to strengthen the new neural connections that control those muscles."}
{"_id": "92a58974", "question": "What are new treatment options for stroke recovery for teenage survivors when botox and physiotherapy are not improving mobility or stability?", "answers": "I am so sorry to hear about that.\nA lot of advancements are being made in the field of nutritional and nutraceutical improvement of brain recovery, neurogenesis, BDNF and NGF release.\nThis is just a doctrinal summary, and an opinion of what I would consider if it was me, but please make sure to always consult with your doctor/specialist.\n1) EPA and DHA (possibly ratio 2:1) from either molecularly distilled fish oil (possibly 5 stars IFOS certificate) or, even better, CO2 supercritical extracted fish oil with antioxidant complex (MINAMI nutrition). Due to the high cost of the second one, I would take one or 2 capsules of it, and the rest from the first one, up to reach 20 grams net of EPA+DHA per day for the first few weeks.\nThen decrease 2–5 grams every couple of weeks and stabilize to a 5 to 7 grams per day.\nThe fish oil has to be taken during the meals, and the meals have to contain fats (good ones, such as avocados, extra virgin olive oil).\n2) Vitamin D3: 10,000 (10 thousands) IU / day, during the meals, with fat, together with the above mentioned fish oil\n3) Acetyl-L-Carnitine ARGINATE + Acetyl-L-Carnitine alone: 1500 mg in the morning, empty stomach, 30 minutes before breakfast. 1000 mg 30 minutes before lunch\n4) 1000 mg Taurine a few minutes before breakfast and dinner. 1000 mg Taurine at bedtime.\n5) A berry extract containing also the species called Vaccinium uliginosum. Such as blueberry pomegranate extract from Life Extension: 1 capsule every 12 hours\n6) CinnamonRich extract of cinnamon (only this, has to be patented and concentrated 10:1 or 12:1, to get rid of the liposoluble compounds that might stress liver otherwise): 1 caps. right before the main meals\n7) Theracurmin: 60 mg 3 times/day during the meals, with fats and with fish oil, together with a piece (size of a small finger) of organic whole tumeric to chew\n8) Gamma Tocopherol (the Vitamin E product has to have much MORE Gamma than Alpha tocopherol!): 1 capsule during the heaviest meal, with fats\n9) Vitamin C + Bioflavonoids, 1000 mg 3 times / day (every 8 hours)\n10) A very broad range of strains of probiotic, 1 per day\n11) A complete and well formulated multivitamin, such as Two-Per-Day capsules\nIt should be continued for a prolonged time.\nI hope this helps.\nAlso, Alon Kaplan ‘s advice about exercising is very good to improve brain recovery and neurogenesis. Make sure to alternate both resistance training and cardio (but not overtraining!).\nFinally, suggested readings:\nEnter the Zone, Barry Sears, PhD\nGrain Brain, David Perlmutter, MD\nIf I could choose only 2 books to read about nutrition, definitely those 2"}
{"_id": "6d0c29d5", "question": "What is the number one way to encourage neuroplasticity and speed up stroke recovery?", "answers": "Repetition. While laying in bed in rehab, I “played” with my fingers for hours on time. Initially, I couldn’t move my affected hand, but as movement came back, I did everything I could. At first, it was just trying to make a fist. When I could sort of do that, I started doing it constantly. Then, I started struggling to touch my thumb to my forefinger, then I tried touching thumb to middle finger…\nWhen I first tried typing, I thought I would never be able to do it again. But I do. When I went back to work, my Occupational Therapist asked what would be hardest. I said using the little finger of my affected hand for the ‘a’, ‘q’ and ‘z’ keys without hitting CapsLock. She gave me a little piece of velcro to put on my CapsLock key. It helped me know that my little finger missed the mark.\nRepeat exercises and other forms of therapy 10x each or as directed by your therapist. Do the entire set three or four times each day. Repeat daily exercises regularly for months or years. Most neurological exercises are simple and don’t fatigue the muscles. The focus is on reconnecting the brain, not building muscle.\nIt has been two years since my stroke, but if I don’t do my exercises at least a couple times every day, I don’t walk or move with as much control. I installed a grab bar for safety doing balance exercises. Initially, I tried using the kitchen counter, but safety 1st!"}
{"_id": "389bee39", "question": "Can a wearable magnetic stimulator aid brain stroke recovery?", "answers": "It MAY! Read about repetitive trans cranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS).\nIt is too early to say as the studies are still on but there are a lot of factors which have to be taken into consideration before even contemplating to start rtms. It most of the cases, it might do more harm than good."}
{"_id": "9c27c2fd", "question": "How can I learn more more about massive stroke recovery and, in particular, what does the patient understand?", "answers": "IMHO, the patient is capable of understanding a hell of a lot more about the process than the doctors!\nThe patient understands that it will take time.\nThe patient knows that there’s no clock — that recovery can occur more than a year after the stroke.\nThe patient know that Recovery” doesn’t mean just learning how to walk again — it means feeling awake again. It means feeling like you can think again. It means conquering the visible AND the invisible. If I had a dollar for every time a neurologist has said, “Wow — you’re as good as new!” I might be able to afford a visit to a neurologist who actually *listens*.\nWhat can you or a doctor do? Listen! Ask the patient how they’re feeling. Read. Look at the ‘recovery’ process other survivors have been through."}
{"_id": "3bf607b0", "question": "What is the most valid measurement tool used for Stroke Recovery Outcome?", "answers": "I have not used stroke assessment scales in a long time and rarely used them when I worked in a rehab center. To a large part it is subjective because of all the factors that can be affected, There are multiple assessment scales of function like speed of ambulation and ability to dress oneself. There is a whole library of assessment tools and different ones will appeal to different clinicians. The most “valid” one may be so detailed that it is impractical for clinical use. Lastly who is doing better the person who can walk faster with a brace vs one walking slower without a brace."}
{"_id": "4893e81c", "question": "Any clinically proven correlations between brain stroke recovery and body inversion exercises?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f064beff", "question": "Are there reasons that Mirtazapine (Remeron) should not be prescribed to dementia or stroke recovery patients?", "answers": "I can answer this somewhat. I stroked while having a craniotomy at 10 months old to remove a astrocytoma giblogangloma ( spelling/ grammar is a learning disability from the stroke so please excuse that). Anyway I have the ability to get seizures so I take Lamictal for it. During my second stay at a psych unit I was placed on Remeron. Once I got home I read the side effects and it didn’t seem too bad so I continued taking it.\nI started gaining weight enough where a lot of my clothes were not fitting anymore. I looked at the side effects again and discovered one way more serious. Ever since taking Remeron when I went to bed some nights my left leg would uncontrollably twitch. With me having the ability to have seizures and it being my partially paralyzed side of my body twitching I stopped it that night.\nA few months later I saw my neurologist and she said I never should of been put on Remeron because of its ability to cause seizures. Be careful with it."}
{"_id": "34519fcb", "question": "Does magnetic stimulation enhance brain activity, aiding stroke recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "824642e3", "question": "Is it good news to feel pain in the paralyzed side of the body during a stroke recovery and why?", "answers": "It was not good news for me. I had no sensation in the paralyzed side, even after I had regained some ability to move it. Then I started feeling pins and needles and a burning sensation. I thought it was just feeling returning and it would pass. But it didn’t. I’ve had that burning pain for three years.\nI recently saw a neurologist at a university hospital who referred me to their pain clinic where they are trying electrical stimulation to relieve this type of pain. I hope it helps."}
{"_id": "72d3bc7e", "question": "A patient aged 80 years old (5 years after a stroke recovery), ulcers are observed on the front of the shin. What can it be, and how can they be treated?", "answers": "I presume that you are under the care of a doctor. You may be diabetic, which reduces circulation and healing responses. This is a common area for ulcers.\nOne of my assistants has an older relative with ulcers that would not heal for a year, despite the recommendations of their doctor and nurse. Antibiotic salves, covered with bandages.\nThey tried a 30% solution of xylitol sugar to wet gazes, then covered it with a bandage. The results were dramatic in a few days. Xylitol can be found in granular form in vitamin and health food stores. Fill a small bottle 1/3rd full with xylitol, then fill the rest with tap water. Shake. It will appear cloudy.\nClean the surface of the ulcers with wet gauze. Pat dry. Place gauze wet with the xylitol solution and cover with a bandage. Replace daily."}
{"_id": "5560d396", "question": "Can your mind heal after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a280e835", "question": "Do people fully recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "21d2500f", "question": "At what point, is recovery from a stroke, impossible?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "057b1386", "question": "What are the chances of recovery for patients suffering from a hemorrhagic stroke of the left side of the brain? By recovery, I am wondering how much of their motor, speech, and other skills they can recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e86a290a", "question": "What is the \"window of opportunity\" regarding therapy for a stroke victim, and what is the time limit set by insurance companies or Medicare?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "821d48f5", "question": "How do you survive a stroke and recover completely as fast as possible?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f10e6a29", "question": "What is the recovery rate from a mini stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "22d54947", "question": "What does the recovery of a cerebellum stroke take?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0553bea8", "question": "Is complete recovery possible after TIA brain stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e2c1084d", "question": "Can increased use of the left hand by aphasics after a stroke aid in recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d80165dd", "question": "Do you think that therapy and early intervention in aphasia are of vital importance for the results of recovery after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2f5cd82b", "question": "How does pneumonia affect Hillary Clinton from a health perspective?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2371695f", "question": "Can a stroke patient hope for a 100% recovery rate after 3 years?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4630439a", "question": "Chance of recovery from second stroke. My father had a second right brain stroke. He was recovering a quite well from first stroke that he had second stroke. What is his chance of recovery to the point of such patients where he recovered last time?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e3d2f9af", "question": "What's the normal recovery period for brain stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c4e0fa3b", "question": "Can a cerebral stroke patient's personality get back as it was after clinical recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4c1a5e18", "question": "How can stroke patients get more convenience and control in their recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bc32c0de", "question": "How do I help a stroke victim on their road to recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "13fe08eb", "question": "What is the best approach to deal with speech recovery after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "16082b43", "question": "What are the recovery chances of a patient having a brain stroke on both sides of the brain?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "aa6e0f08", "question": "How was the path to recovery for your loved one after a stroke?", "answers": "I was age 39 when I had a massive ischemic stroke. I was fortunate to have several therapists working with me. I can tell you a hit to the brain like a stroke is very much energy draining. I too slept a lot. I agree with Holly, she probably is aware of more going on around her than you think. I recognized people and was able to respond. But depending on what part of the brain that was injured makes all the difference. Was her speech center of the brain affected? She may need speech therapy to relearn how to speak. Do you have access to medical care specializing in brain injury? I was told I would ‘never’ get better, never walk, blah blah. I DID get better! Raised 2 awesome children who were babies at the time. I walked a breast cancer 60 mile walk in 3 days. Most people that meet me can not even tell I ever had a brain injury.\nNever.ever give up. The human spirit is STRONG. I would talk with her doctor and get a medical opinion. Then sit back and watch her get stronger and stronger.\nA stroke is a ‘BIG Deal’ I’m sorry your mom and family are having to go through this. It is HARD for all involved. Depending on her health before the stroke and the severity of the stroke with good therapy and good medical care I pray she will get stronger everyday. I continued to improve up to 2 years post stroke. You are a good person to care for your mom. Blessings."}
{"_id": "6be1bb4d", "question": "What are the latest methods of treatment and recovery after suffering a stroke?", "answers": "They will be in a hospital for a few days to monitor their health, once cleared they will be taken to a rehabilitation hospital where they may be for a month or more. There they will be taken care of and will go through speech and physical therapy. It’s vital up support a person in this situation as they will feel alone and will want you to be there to help them and support them. Also be very patient with them and listen to them."}
{"_id": "a265a0ee", "question": "Can any person who is paralysed from his left side due to stroke recover fully? Can any stroke patient here share his/her stroke paralysis recovery journey? How much% have you recovered?", "answers": "It’s been 9 years since I had hemorrhage aneurysm. It was pretty severe, about 25% of right side brain was dead. Lucky to survive. First few years were miserable. None stop pain in my left sides. Especially joints. left hand was in tight clench and couldn’t open up or any relaxation, as well as left foot and all the toes curled down. I’ve been pretty diligent about walking, exercising for years. Going through depression and pain managing, I started meditation, tai chi, going up the hill/mountain daily. Few years later switched going up the hill to swimming. I tried alternative medicine, tcm(traditional Chinese medicine: received and studied) massage, etc. I guess I have improved, specially my attitude and outlook in life. Pain is almost gone and whenever it comes I manage it with cannabis, both thc and cdb. I was worried about repercussions but after few years of trying not doing it, first time was magical.. no pain and I was even getting motivated and enjoying for few hours until effect lasted. Realizing and accepting life is short and might as well enjoy best you can, you just have to let go and do whatever at this stage.\nPhysically I’m still limping and left hand is still not functioning but it’s lot looser.\nI try to be as independent as possible. Driving is one of important thing for getting around and comforts. I still haven’t given up yet I’m not expecting 100% either. After many years of frustration, last thing I wanted was to play guitar again but finally trying to completely let it go, being almost 10 years now."}
{"_id": "57b1a740", "question": "Can hyperbaric oxygen therapy improve recovery from a stroke?", "answers": "As others have noted, some studies have shown that HBOT can improve some symptoms associated with acute ischemic stroke. The earlier in the disease process the better.\nUnfortunately, many hospitals do not use it for such, as it is not an approved diagnosis by the Undersea & Hyperbaric Medical Society, so it is unlikely to be covered by insurance. (This may vary in some states) so most hospital associated chambers will not be able to treat you, especially if they have contracts with Medicare and Medicaid (neither that will pay for HBOT in stroke cases)\nIf your insurance does not pay for therapy, there are many private hyperbaric clinics that will take private payment, quite often an amount close to what your copay might have been anyway, so look for those options."}
{"_id": "9ede924f", "question": "Can we create a 2 stroke electric motor (work stroke and recovery/recharge) that is similar to a 2-stroke combustion engine (compression and working stroke)?", "answers": "So you would want a linear motor, something like a solenoid, that would provide power in one direction, but then regenerate power in the reverse. How would it return to home? You would need some sort of outside force to return the mechanism to home position. Now the problem comes to how you do this.\nIf you have a spring on the setup to push it back home, then on the outward stroke you will have to use additional power to overcome the spring that will return it to home position. The energy needed to extend the spring will always be more than you can generate by the return stroke.\nIf you have some outside force to return the spring, then you still need to overcome that force on the outward stroke. So either way, it take a lot more energy to extend this linear motor than you can generate from it.\nSo yes, we could create one. The question is why would we want to? Yes there are some specialized application where this could be useful. However in general use, it doesn’t gain you anything. The laws of physics and thermodynamics say that we will never be able to come close to breaking even on the power generated. You are adding a large amount of complexity with little practical return."}
{"_id": "bf22bec6", "question": "Is the treatment for and recovery rate from a stroke much better today than back in the 1960s or 70s?", "answers": "In the US, treatment of acute stroke is nothing short of revolutionary. Patients who come in unable to talk or walk have a reasonable chance of walking out of the hospital 3 days later.\nMany US medical center have an acute stroke team. They require an emergency MRI, read in real time by a stroke neurologist and reviewed by an interventional radiologist. The patient then is in the cath lab and the interventional radiologist removes the clot from the brain using a newly designed catheter that is purchased by the hospital at $9,000 per unit.\nLast year my medical center treated their first acute stroke that way, a 60 year old man who could not walk and could not talk with half of his body paralyzed. He walked out unassisted 3 days later and spoke normally with only a slight hesitancy in speech but completely and easily understandable. He was on the front page of a local paper the following week.\nIf an emergency room and hospital don’t have that capability, ideally the patient should be moved by paramedic ambulance or helicopter ASAP to a center that does. If brain tissue dies due to lack of oxygen, then the neurological problems are by and large permanent.\nhttps://www.heart.org/-/media/files/about-us/policy-research/fact-sheets/facts-cornerstones-for-soc-primary-stroke-centers.pdf?la=en"}
{"_id": "fbbf081d", "question": "What are the recovery chances after a pontine stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "95db5bcd", "question": "Are there any chances of recovery for vision loss due to a stroke for an age 32 patient with migraine history (3 years)?", "answers": "What you need to know. About one-third of stroke survivors experience vision loss. Most people who have vision loss after a stroke do not fully recover their vision. Some recovery is possible – this will usually happen in the first few months after a stroke. Stroke can happen to anyone at any age. Carla Nash"}
{"_id": "24ad54ed", "question": "How do recovery periods differ for different types of strokes?", "answers": "As I understand it, hemmhoragic (sp?) strokes are generally larger than ischemic strokes and therefore more difficult to recover from.\nPersonally, I suffered from several ischemic strokes and have had doctors meet me and declare that, “Wow, you fully recovered!” I always dread those conversations. I have a lot of invisible deficits; I can’t write by hand, I’m ‘allergic’ to sunlight, I hate noisy places, and I cry in lots of inappropriate scenarios, such as when i hear loud music. (Marching bands, most notably.) Most of all, though, I’m tired. Some (most?) days, I wake up tired; some days, I have to go someplace noisy/crowded, and I get tired; some (many) days, it’s sunny out and I get tired. I’m too tired to drive. I’m often too tired to take care of my five yo. It just plain sucks.\nI’m ten years out. I am getting better, but it’s slow, and I suspect I’m on an asymptote that doesn’t really ever hit normal again. I caution you to refine your question of ‘recovery’ and NOT discuss it with patients as if they’re ok or are going to be ok, because you just don’t know if they will."}
{"_id": "331ee42e", "question": "What are some experiences of hand mobility recovery after a stroke? My dad had a stroke a few days ago and his left leg is weak but mobile, but the left hand is not moving.", "answers": "The key is repetition and movement. It’s not enough to massage it, there has to be intent on the part of the patient to try and move the hand. Or any limb that due to a stroke has lost some function.\nRemember that a stroke is actual damage to the brain. A clot thrown off, a vessel that tears within the brain, really any trauma that causes an escalating group of symptoms that ends in some form of loss to the body and our ability to move or think, due to damage to the brain, usually in a localized area.\nThe brain has to rewire itself to take over functions, and if the damage is not to great, recovery is at least partial to complete given time. There is no way to predict how much time or how much of a recovery is possible.\nYet I can tell you that recovery is based on daily, even hourly habits of effort and practice, and continuing the process throughout the rest of your life.\nYou are rebuilding connections, and trying to move your hand sends a signal out, giving the brain direction and effort, while at the same time, going through therapy sending signals up to the brain. The bombardment from both directions will enhance the chance of the brain adapting to the newer pathways.\nUltimately though, you should talk with your doctor, and the therapist for the proper types of exercises, how much much damage is there, and also if there are any other ongoing issues that might contribute to further problems."}
{"_id": "1ead9554", "question": "Is complete recovery from stroke symptoms possible?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "66eb00bd", "question": "Is it possible to do liposuction for a stroke patient (after 6 months)? Will it help their health recovery? How will it affect their health?", "answers": "Hello liposuction has nothing to do with stroke recovery.. We did do liposuction for a young paraplegic who's thighs were constantly rubbing against each other and also the weight was hampering with his rehab.. Kindly consult a plastic surgeon."}
{"_id": "6c58876b", "question": "Is complete recovery possible after a decompressive craniectomy for a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ae50c9a5", "question": "Of course rehab, but outside of rehab, what is a good way to help speed up recovery from a hemorrhagic stroke, like to wake up nerves and such?", "answers": "Not sure I know what you mean by “wake up nerves”. During a brain hemorrhage, neurons are destroyed by contact with blood. The Blood-Brain Barrier normally protects delicate neurons. When that is breached, the affected part of the brain dies. It will never wake up.\nThere is a thin ring around the destroyed area of the brain that is probably damaged by the increased pressure from the hemorrhage that may recover, but that simply takes time.\nThe brain can “rewire” around the damaged area, which is what rehab is designed to stimulate. The more repetitions of the stupid exercises you do, the more effectively the brain will rewire. This is true of speech therapy as well as physical therapy and occupational therapy.\nIf you’re asking about sensation, as in “waking up” the ability to feel things, the problem isn’t in the face, trunk, arm or leg. The problem is in the brain’s processing of input from the regions outside the brain. How long it takes for the brain to regain the ability to process sensory input properly will vary and depends on the region of the stroke.\nI had a profound loss of sensation on the affected side. About a month after my stroke, my brother and SIL visited me in rehab. I said how much my neck hurt from my shoulder and arm just hanging like dead meat. My brother stood behind my chair and gave me a vigorous shoulder rub. I said that felt really good and asked him to rub the affected side. My SIL’s eyes widened. Apparently, he’d been rubbing both sides equally. He also gave my arm an acupressure massage. I could feel it when he really dug in and it “hurt good.” I don’t know it the vigorous, deep, stimulating massage had an effect, but within a few days, I began feeling the affected side again.\nWhen touched I felt a burning sensation and I felt “pins and needles” all the time. I thought that would go away once things settled. Four and a half years later, I’m still waiting. When stroke affects the thalamus, it sometimes sets off a pain syndrome originally called “Thalamic Pain Syndrome”. Apparently that is what I have. I’ve consulted various neurologists over the years and they’ve given me a “ladder” of treatment options.\nIf you want more info, reply and we can discuss in the comments."}
{"_id": "0b824f57", "question": "What's the likelihood of making complete a recovery from a really bad stroke?", "answers": "I would love to answer with a number, a reassuring tale…..\nBut\nI've treated more than 1000 stroke patients as a physical therapist in a ward specialized in stroke rehab. And the best answer I can give is my honest experience.\nA severe stroke, is major damage to the brain, a huge volume is dead (forever, not coming back), and a sphere around it that's in chock. Some of the neurons in the sphere might recover to a degree (from not at all to full function). If it's a bleed than it's way more complicated.\nRemember the dead area, will never recover - after a while there will only be scar tissue in the area. The area in chock experience swelling, chemical imbalances and more.\nIf it's a blood clot and it's treated rapidly and correctly, damage can be reduced to an amazing degree. That's why you always call 911 if you suspect a stroke immediately !!\nInter cranial bleeding is much more complicated, and the damage will depend on a lot of factors.\nA big blood clot will most of the time block the Middle Cerebral Artery some where. That is bad, the artery supplies blood to a huge area including sensory inputs, motor control plus a number of other important areas on the brain like speech.\nIf it's a clot, the sphere in chock will recover and initially the patient will get better fast. If they are treated early (the clot is removed or dissolve). The dead zone might be small and symptoms will be small. But we are talking about a major stroke - so the left or right side is paralyzed and often the person will experience some symptoms like chronic tiredness, cognitive deficits, personality changes, paralysis in some degree, pain, numbness, partial blindness, loss of speech, loss of understanding language…..\nSo no. Unless the person gets to a big hospital with a neurological ward maybe even a neurosurgeon fast (Hours), there's no chance for complete recovery.\nI'm sorry but, nobody gets by a severe stroke without some symptoms,\nHope that helps, remember they need you to be there for them. But always ask before helping. Give them the time to do whatever they can by and for themselves."}
{"_id": "59dfc816", "question": "What is the chance of recovery from a basal stem stroke?", "answers": "Hi, just as with any other stroke, the likelihood of recovery from a brain stem stroke depends on a lot of things, most importantly the size of the infarct and its location. It also depends on what interventions if any were performed and when, as well as patient factors such as age, history of prior strokes, and comorbid conditions. It also depends on what level of function you want to count as recovery.\nStroke recovery prognosis can be difficult for all these reasons. I would suggest it's probably best to talk to a neurologist who is familiar with the individual case."}
{"_id": "47ac4b1f", "question": "Yesterday my grandma had a stroke, she hadn’t received help for 12 hours and is now paralyzed on the entire left side of her body. Does anybody know the odds of her recovering or ways to improve her recovery?", "answers": "They used to say if a person comes to the hospital within 3 hours of a stroke ,Brain damage can be prevented.But the new study suggests that the traditional three-hour time window is too short. By combining data from multiple clinical trials, Maarten Lansberg, MD, PhD, assistant professor of neurology and neurological sciences at Stanford, and colleagues from Belgium and Germany showed that treatment can benefit patients up to 4.5 hours after they experience their first symptom. Their findings were published online May 21 in the journal Stroke.\nEvery year, more than 750,000 Americans experience a stroke, or brain attack, due to a sudden drop in blood flow to the brain. Most strokes are ischemic, meaning they're caused by a blocked artery. For these strokes, a medication called tissue plasminogen activator, or tPA, can open blocked blood vessels and help restore blood flow to the brain.\nIdeally one should go to a hospital where they can go through the groin vein and remove the blood clot in the brain.\nSigns of stroke\nFace: Smile and see if one side of the face droops.\nArms: Raise both arms. Does one arm drop down?\nSpeech: Say a short phrase and check for slurred or strange speech.\nTime: If the answer to any of these is yes, call 911 right away and write down the time when symptoms started.\nWarning Signs\nSometimes a stroke happens gradually, but you’re likely to have one or more sudden symptoms like these:\nNumbness or weakness in your face, arm, or leg, especially on one side\nConfusion or trouble understanding other people\nDifficulty speaking\nTrouble seeing with one or both eyes\nProblems walking or staying balanced or coordinated\nDizziness\nA severe headache that comes on for no reason\nIf you have these symptoms, call 911 even if you’re not sure you’re having a stroke.\n3 Types of Strokes\nIschemic Strokes (Clots)\nIschemic strokes\noccur as a result of an obstruction within a blood vessel supplying blood to the brain. The underlying condition for this type of obstruction is the development of fatty deposits lining the vessel walls. This condition is called atherosclerosis. These fatty deposits can cause two types of obstruction:\nCerebral thrombosis refers to a thrombus (blood clot) that develops at the clogged part of the vessel.\nCerebral embolism refers generally to a blood clot that forms at another location in the circulatory system, usually the heart and large arteries of the upper chest and neck. A portion of the blood clot breaks loose enters the bloodstream and travels through the brain’s blood vessels until it reaches vessels too small to let it pass. A second important cause of embolism is an irregular heartbeat, known as atrial fibrillation. It creates conditions where clots can form in the heart, dislodge and travel to the brain.\nHemorrhagic Strokes (Bleeds)\nHemorrhagic\nstroke\naccounts for about 13 percent of stroke cases. It results from a weakened vessel that ruptures and bleeds into the surrounding brain. The blood accumulates and compresses the surrounding brain tissue. The two types of hemorrhagic strokes are intracerebral (within the brain) hemorrhage or subarachnoid hemorrhage. Hemorrhagic stroke occurs when a weakened blood vessel ruptures. Two types of weakened blood vessels usually cause hemorrhagic stroke. An aneurysm is a ballooning of a weakened region of a blood vessel. If left untreated, the aneurysm continues to weaken until it ruptures and bleeds into the brain. An arteriovenous malformation (AVM) is a cluster of abnormally formed blood vessels. Any one of these vessels can rupture, also causing bleeding into the brain.\nTransient Ischemic Attack (TIA)\nTIAs are often labeled mini-strokes\nbecause they can be relatively benign in terms of immediate consequences. But the term “warning stroke” is more appropriate for these temporary episodes, because they can indicate the likelihood of a coming stroke. A TIA is a temporary blockage of blood flow to the brain. The blockage is short-term or temporary during a TIA or warning stroke. The clot may dissolve on it its own or get dislodged so that it stops causing the symptoms. Temporary symptoms may occur. A third of U.S. adults have had symptoms consistent with a TIA. The symptoms are similar to an ischemic stroke, but TIA symptoms usually last less than five minutes with an average of about a minute. When a TIA is over, that particular blockage usually causes no permanent injury to the brain.\nSorry about your grandma.She will have to go through physical therapy and will be able to walk ."}
{"_id": "0dfb4676", "question": "What are the chances of recovery for patients after ischemic stroke?", "answers": "Ischemic stroke happens when arteries to the brain are blocked and blood cannot reach the brain .It can affect many functions and also cause paralysis. The brain cells begin to die minutes after the stroke. So it is best to rush the patient to a medical doctor immidiately. Chances of recovery are very good if the patient is given medical help as soon as possible best within 3 hours of the attack . The doctor gives clot busting medicine and the patient starts recovering. My husband too suffered from ischemic stroke and has recovered fully . He got a paralytic attack and the right side of his body was in the process of getting paralysed. I got to know something was wrong as his voice changed and he spoke in blurred sentences and his right hand could not lift his spoon at the dining table and was falling flat and rushed him to hospital emergency where he was given clot dissolving medicine in the stretcher itself before he was put in the bed and he recovered fully. He smokes, has type 2 diabetes and has high cholestrol and high blood pressure. Now he takes medicine to control diabetes , walks a lot and takes blood thinning medicines and lives a normal life. People are not aware of the symptoms therefore there is a delay in taking them to the Doctor many a time. But, it is possible for a patient to recover fully as in my husband’s case through allopathic medicine."}
{"_id": "f1b3152e", "question": "Have you experienced a right-side, MCA stroke? What was your experience of recovery like?", "answers": "I had a right side thalamic hemorrhage. Every stroke is different, but my experience is that recovery depends on the time you put into repeating “trivial” exercises and your determination to recover.\nWhile in rehab, I was stuck in bed when not with a therapist, so as soon as I attained the ability to make a fist I did finger exercises hour after hour. My therapists said that the affected side can “learn from the non-affected side, so I did them with both hands. Initially, I couldn’t reliably touch my thumb to each finger in turn, but by watching the affected hand, I eventually managed it. Later, I was able to do it without watching. Now, I can type with 10 fingers, though I sometimes miss with my little finger. I hit CAPS LOCK instead of ‘a’, for instance.\nI lost proprioception, but some of that returned. I still have to check where my foot is before I stand up and walk. When getting out of an Uber, I forgot about my foot. It was tucked somewhere, and I fell. I can walk with a single point cane to help with balance. On smooth, even surfaces, I don’t even need the cane.\nI was in rehab for almost 6 weeks, then had in-home rehab for another six weeks. I returned to work after 5 months. Neuroplasticity is your friend. Do the stupid exercises over and over and over every day. It does help.\nGood luck!"}
{"_id": "c9822072", "question": "Are there any good books I can read to help with the recovery from a stroke, for speech/rehabilitation?", "answers": "My favorite book on stroke recovery did not address specific therapies but talked about the recovery process. It is called Navigating the Complexities of Stroke by Louis R Caplan.\nEvery stroke is different and everyone has a different recovery path. The key is staying with it and doing the exercises your therapists give you, even after you stop seeing the therapist regularly.\nThere is hope. Work hard and don’t give up. The exercises help, if you do them over and over and over and over, every day, week after week, month after month. Record yourself now and again after six months. You’ll be amazed by the progress you see. Day to day, it is hard to notice improvement but the small improvements add up if you keep working."}
{"_id": "c19ceab7", "question": "Is recovery from a stroke in a diabetic person difficult than a non-diabetic person?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0db8e61b", "question": "How may the microbiome boost the brain’s recovery from stroke damage?", "answers": "Microbiome diet is trendy nutrients therapy which help in weight loss and it faster metabolism rate. Perhaps this is not sufficient to boost brain recovery in case of brain stroke . Our brain and whole body needs all the nutrients not just a diet that provide limited source of nutrients . Like our body needs protein , minerals like zinc , iron , folic acid , potassium , calcium ……needs vitamins like B 1 , B2 , B6…..vitamin C and other vitamins and nutrients that help in faster recovery .\nHence nutritious food and balanced diet , all fruits and vegetables , nuts and dry fruits , milk products and other nutritious food provide us all the nutrients that is necessary for recovery of diseases , growth and development of body . Thanks."}
{"_id": "5ab6b444", "question": "(Serious) Those who have had a stroke, or know someone that has, how was your recovery?", "answers": "S-L-O-W! I had a massive stroke 20 years ago! A week before I delivered my last baby. I started in rehab right away, sent to the OB unit and was sent back to the rehab unit. The ‘typical’ brain rewires itself around the ‘affected’ part of the brain for 2–3 YEARS post stroke. I was told by my Dr. I had 2 years but I noticed some things returning up to 2.5 years post stroke! The best advice I can give you is to immobilize the affected arm and FORCE your affected arm to do everything. This was not done to me in therapy, but it would’ve helped me so much. Cool thing when you lose use of an arm or hand his buddy the unaffected arm tries to help his ‘friend’ Help those neurons reconnect faster by forcing yourself to use it! I still have some spasticity in my affected hand and I’ll never be able to wear heels again. But, if you were to see me at the store you would never be able to tell I ever had a stroke! The brain s an AMAZING organ!"}
{"_id": "ae0eecaf", "question": "Is there a difference in recovery from a stroke between introverts and extroverts?", "answers": "I don’t see why I/E would affect something totally unrelated to type like that. Perhaps, inasmuch as the recovery might involve interacting with other people there might be some difference? But that has notheing to do with the specific instance of a stroke, and whatever difference probably won’t be much."}
{"_id": "6583d4fe", "question": "What is the recovery time for a dog bladder post spinal stroke?", "answers": "What do you mean by “spinal stroke?” It is a term I have not heard before.\nDo you mean some kind of spinal injury? If so, a loss of bladder control is possible.\nTypically, the animal will lose the ability to engage the muscles that squeeze the bladder empty. Consequently, the bladder will continue to fill with urine, which ultimately leaks out somewhat continually. It is distressing to the animal and probably very uncomfortable, too. Think of how you feel when your bladder is uncomfortably full.\nIncontinence pads or bands (for male dogs) can help with the urine discharge, but they do not help the animal’s distress. Some medications may be beneficial, as is catheterization.\nYour Vet is the best source of information on this issue, because it depends on where the injury was and what type of injury it was."}
{"_id": "f537686f", "question": "Can 100% recovery possible on middle cerebral arterial stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c4b7cce8", "question": "What is the percentage of recovery due to a stroke caused by high blood pressure?", "answers": "Your question is actually impossible to answer based on the dearth of information you have provided. A \"stroke\" is called a CVA (CerebroVascular Accident) and can be caused by thrombosis or rupture of a vessel supplying the brain. Hypertensive CVAs can affect any part of the brain, any number of the vessels directly distal to the point of rupture, plus any spillage of blood on to the brain itself.\nThe preceding is not to negate the existence of some rough average as to range of partial recovery. I just don’t know what that is."}
{"_id": "9a6ad293", "question": "A 19-year-old has a stroke and is paralyzed from the neck down. What are her chances of making a recovery/being able to walk again?", "answers": "A 19 year old with a stroke is unusual but with a diagnoses of paralysis from the neck down it doesn’t sound good if this is complete paralysis necrosis in the cervical nervous system involvement but if the blood flow is restored from the stroke is may be temporary or incomplete paralysis and would have a much better outcome. It basically depends on what the nerve involvement is with this stroke and at what cervical nerves are involved. A neurologist is most undoubtedly involved in the prognosis and that is good and if there is a spinal rehabilitation center close by for rehab this would be essential to therapy. i can only hope and pray that it is incomplete paralysis and hope the 19 year old has the stamina for his or her job of gettin well as it will take all that person has to get as much function back as they can."}
{"_id": "6ade29d3", "question": "Do you think that aspirin reduces the size of the damaged area of the brain and initiated the repair of mechanisms and improves behavioral recovery after an ischemic stroke?", "answers": "Aspirin does not reduce the size of the damaged area of the brain or “initiate repair mechanisms” after an ischemic stroke. When ischemic strokes block blood flow to part of the brain, the part of the brain that does not receive blood dies. It cannot be repaired.\nWith therapy, neuroplasticity can “rewire” around the damage, but the damage is permanent. It will show on CT scans for the rest of the stroke survivor’s life.\nI’ve regained function since my (hemorrhagic) stroke thanks to lots of physical and occupation therapy. I’m still doing my PT exercises at home. I saw my original PT by chance recently and he was impressed! He said I must have done hundreds of thousands of reps to have recovered so well. But I have a fluid-filled hole in my brain — the damaged area has been washed away over the years since my stroke.\n‘"}
{"_id": "cf9ea2cf", "question": "In first aid, what are all the recovery positions for heart attack, stroke, seizure and cardiac arrest?", "answers": "Fit? Fit?\nDo you mean seizure ?\nFor everything except cardiac arrest and seizure, the recovery position is that of comfort and safety while the EMTs arrive. Slightly raising the head and shoulders is pretty effective.\nCardiac arrest means that the heart has stopped. There is no recovery position. The position is that of providing CPR, again, while waiting for the EMTs.\nIf it's a Hallmark movie type of seizure, more professionally known as epilepsy with a grand mal seizure, help the person to safely lie down and move hard objects out of the way. When the seizure stops, roll them to one side and make sure that they are able to breathe easily. EMTs.\nLesser seizure activity, if possible, sitting down works. When I have my episodes, I don't want to lie down. I also don't want to be left alone. I'll let you know about the EMTs, but because my speech becomes very slurred and I stutter badly for several hours, it may be difficult for me to speak. But I'm an RN and incredibly stubborn about these things."}
{"_id": "276f873f", "question": "What percentage of stroke patients make a full recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3d47df1f", "question": "Is physical recovery different between brain damage resulting from stroke, from cerebral haemorrhage, from blunt force trauma and from encephalitis?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a1373274", "question": "Is RTMS treatment helpful for stroke patients for motor recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6e12039e", "question": "Do you think these apps are good to stroke survivors for their faster recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c64fa5d4", "question": "How can a speech therapist help with recovery after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "84c6c19c", "question": "What is the role of power strokes and recovery strokes in paramecium?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "075d24a5", "question": "Does a 2nd stroke slow down a person’s recovery time?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e674b19a", "question": "How do you cure a stroke completely and have a full recovery within a few days?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3e24a061", "question": "What is the best predictor of upper limb motor recovery after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e2fb3c3f", "question": "My mum had a stroke but is on the road to recovery, but is a reoccurrence more likely now she's had one?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "fb9eeff7", "question": "How does gene therapy help functional recovery after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0a622fbe", "question": "How do you set up a room for a loved one who has had a stroke to optimize functional recovery?", "answers": "Buy grab bars on Amazon and mount them in the bathroom and shower. Consider a Toto Washlet bidet. It’s nice to not need your caregiver to wipe your behind.\nAlso fresh air and sunlight to combat depression, which is very common among stroke survivors.\nAlso, check out my site:\nhttp://Strokesite.com/gadgets-devices\nfor some other cool stuff that helped me."}
{"_id": "86abe667", "question": "How do you break up with someone that's currently in recovery/rehab following a stroke? They still love you, but while you still care, you don't love them back. You don't want to affect the results of their recovery by depressing them while in rehab", "answers": "Really bad timing! really bad and suspect!\nwhy wait until now to clue in this person that you just don’t feel for them as they feel for you?\nnow if you warned them you had no intention of getting serious and they didn’t listen, that’s one thing. But it doesn’t sound like that. You are asking how to break up!\nplease stop worrying about how you may impede their recovery! It sounds like too little too late to be worrying about them at this point! It sounds shallow!\nany breakup will throw the recipient off!\nWhat will throw them off even more is realizing you were stringing them along for so long knowing how they felt\nand you’re speaking breakup! So you and the person presumably had something to break up from!\nit’s a tangled web we weave when first we practice to deceive!"}
{"_id": "d57bf7d7", "question": "How are you doing now, one year after suffering your stroke? I am interested in your recovery. Could you share that?", "answers": "…I still have residual inability to fully function due to the limitations on my left side. This has been present from the third month. However, my recovery has been miraculous in, my opinion. Compared with just after my stroke what I am able to accomplish today is tremendous. I feel and perform most simple activities well but coordination is still an issue hence my walking is still affected.\nNonetheless, my recovery is still showing signs of improvement and I remain determined to recover fully."}
{"_id": "ca92bc04", "question": "How long does it take to recover from a mild stroke? What is the recovery process?", "answers": "There are so many variables that impact recovery.\nLocation of stroke: cerebral cortex, cerebellum, versus brainstem\nArteries impacted: striate arteries, anterior cerebral, middle cerebral, posterior cerebral, versus circle of Willis\nHow do you define a mild stroke: TIAs (transient ischemic attack), aphasia, speech loss, hearing loss, hemi-paraplegia, paraplegia, hemiplegia, quadriplegia, etc.\nVarious combinations of the above, will range short times to long times."}
{"_id": "4816a1ac", "question": "Do you think task-specific training is more effective for a stroke patient's recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "49ee76bd", "question": "What is the recovery time for a 21 year old who has had hemorrhagic stroke on the left side of the brain? It was caught very early, will she forget us?", "answers": "Q: “What is the recovery time for a 21 year old who has had hemorrhagic stroke on the left side of the brain? It was caught very early, will she forget us?”\nThe recovery time depends on the extent of the stroke and where it occurred. See Victoria Rehn’s answer for more information.\nI suggest you be thankful that the stroke is in the left hemisphere. Damage to the left side will cause many difficulties, but I assure you she will not forget you. I recommend you read two books about left-hemisphere damage that have positive outcomes.\nMy Stroke of Insight: A Brain Scientist's Personal Journey: Taylor, Jill Bolte: 9780452295544: Amazon.com: Books\nhttps://www.amazon.com/My-Stroke-Insight-Scientists-Personal/dp/0452295548\nDr. Taylor’s book is about a massive left hemisphere stroke. I think you will benefit from reading the book, but you can also look for her TED talk.\nGabby: A Story of Courage and Hope: Giffords, Gabrielle, Kelly, Mark, Zaslow, Jeffrey: 9781451661064: Amazon.com: Books\nhttps://www.amazon.com/Gabby-Story-Courage-Gabrielle-Giffords/dp/1451661061\nGabby’s “stroke” was a gunshot to the left hemisphere, but I believe it is also applicable to a left hemisphere stroke. She and her husband also gave a TED talk.\nStories of right hemisphere strokes are not so positive concerning memories of loved ones. Evidence suggest that emotional memories of loved ones are stored in the right hemisphere, usually unimpacted by damage to the left.\nI wish you good fortune on your journey with a stroke victim. You will have time to read both books."}
{"_id": "e75f0819", "question": "What are my chances of recovery from smoking-related diseases such as cardiac disease, lung cancer, chronic pulmonary disease (including emphysema), and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ad3cd460", "question": "If there is an acute infract in the mid brain and pons area after the age of 60 is there any treatment which can make recovery to become normal again after the brain stroke attack due to blood clot there?", "answers": "I understand your desperation, fear, anger, that someone relatively young gets so damaged, most probably irreparably. So sorry.\nThe area damaged is a very important area.\nHim being in a coma for such a long time doesn't bode well, you must prepare yourself for the worst.\nWhat would you expect the neurosurgeon to be able to do when operating? Brain tissue has been lost (= is dead) because of a blood clot stopping blood flow to the area, so no oxygen, no surgery can ever repair this.\nI wouldn't expect too much in terms of regaining meaningful functional life whatever they're trying to do for him."}
{"_id": "49735d23", "question": "What programs are available to veterans to assist during recovery from heart attack or stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "98d4aa73", "question": "How long does a covid patient remain at risk of heart stroke after recovery?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "140ebfdb", "question": "Are there any updates on how acupuncture methods can improve upper limbs recovery of stroke patients?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e86cf46d", "question": "What are the odds of a decent recovery from a rather large stroke on the right side of the brain if the patient has had surgery to remove the clot? The patient being in the middle 70s and in good health up until this.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9fcc21b8", "question": "My 37 year old husband had a thalamic stroke. What are some specific things I can do at home to make the cognitive recovery easier for him?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4667004b", "question": "My nan had a severe stroke. She lives alone and wasn’t found for over 10 hours. If she was found earlier, would her chances of recovery be higher?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6a9c5da9", "question": "Which is better for stroke paralysis recovery, stem cells or the much cheaper perispinal etanercept?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c3198588", "question": "What is the time limit for the full recovery of a 50 year old female patient with a left brain stroke? Will she regain/recall all her past and will she be able to do all that she was doing before stroke struck her?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6a694aeb", "question": "I traveled to the US in 2014 spent (120 days) and now wish to visit my dad struggling with recovery from a stroke & covid. I Need advise on the best approach in applying for a B1/B2 visa or is there any alternate visa type(s) applicable?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e25f0405", "question": "I'm a survivor of a massive hemorrhagic stroke, but whenever I use the term cognitive reserve to answer questions about recovery, people are quick to shoot it down. why is it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5f752889", "question": "Do you think that aspirin reduces the size of the damaged area of the brain and initiated the repair of mechanisms and improves behavioral recovery after an ischemic stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8f87a396", "question": "Is it bad for your health to take medical drugs when you don't need them? This is for a 30 day study where I will be taking drugs for the \"recovery of motor (movement), speech, cognition (thinking) and other neurological issues\" of stroke patients.", "answers": "Possibly. I also got to ask why did they let you in this trial? Either, they are testing if its safe (if its not your gonna be hating life) or you lied to get in this trial and you are doing nothing but bad for all those that might be reliant on the drug."}
{"_id": "b1442bf3", "question": "After a stroke which processes occur in damaged brain tissues? I mean from a point when tissues suffer from hypoxia to a recovery stage when a brain adapts to it's new condition. Which complications could a patient get?", "answers": "I’m not sure what you’re looking for. I had a hemorrhage in my brain (hemorrhagic stroke). They watched me closely for about 24 hours looking for signs of pressure inside the cranium that would require emergency surgery. Then they did another CT scan to check whether the bleeding had stopped. If it hadn’t stopped, I would have needed surgery to stop it.\nA Speech Therapist tested my ability to swallow on the 2nd day. I’d had nothing by mouth at that point. My swallowing was not perfect, so they put me on thickened liquids (yuck!) and soft foods. They didn’t want me to aspirate food or drink and develop bacterial pneumonia.\nMy blood pressure was sky high during the acute stroke, and they lowered it very slowly to avoid shocking the brain with the change in pressure. I was in ICU for two weeks until my BP was under 160. Then, I was transferred to a critical care telemetry unit.\nThe blood that had leaked into my brain had burst into one of the ventricles and displaced the cerebrospinal fluid that normally fills the ventricles. The blood drained slowly into my spine, causing a ferocious headache that lasted over a week. The headache was painful, but harmless.\nThe nurses watched over the side that was paralyzed. They carefully positioned my “useless” arm on a pillow. They kept my “dead” leg covered and warm. I couldn’t feel anything on that side, so the nurses were making sure I did not harm myself by getting into a position that cut off blood flow to a limb.\nMy affected arm hung like dead weight from my shoulder. It pulled on the shoulder joint all the way across to my neck. I couldn’t feel anything except the deep pain of the strained muscles or tendons, but it felt nice when the nurses rubbed liniment into the area. They placed my arm on a pile of pillows to support it and protect the shoulder joint.\nThat is about all I remember about complications in my case, but when I got to rehab and worked in groups of stroke survivors, I saw that many of them had ugly craniotomy incisions. A craniotomy has many risks of complications as well, though since I didn’t need one (thank goodness!)I don’t know what they are.\nIn my first week of rehab, I was assessed for deficits. They tested my limbs, my eyesight, my sensation, my strength, etc. They also tested me for cognitive deficits in memory, attention, executive function, and other things."}
{"_id": "fd1397c3", "question": "Is there any evidence of post-stroke rehabilitation exercise performance correlation with recovery assessment of motor function?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "686555be", "question": "Is stem cell treatment for paralysis reliable in India? Which center is best ?Does stem cells really have the capability to repair damaged part of brain tissue due to stroke? Can we expect assured recovery?", "answers": "This is experimental treatment and as such is only available in a clinical trials. I'm not aware of any hospital able to \"fix\" a stroke with stem cells."}
{"_id": "a4704485", "question": "Is it possible to buy post-accident international health insurance? My father-in-law had a stroke. I’m looking at options to support recovery (no previous insurance) & he is in Moldova. I need insurance that will allow us to have him treated abroad.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "13333c36", "question": "What can you suggest me for speedy recovery from hemiplegia on the left side of my body due to brain stroke? How long shall it take to recover to the best a person can? How long did it take you to reach a stage where you can do tasks?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4712f278", "question": "Do you know or been through experience of perinatal stroke with happy recovery, and living the normal life without anyone noticing the effects?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "47e6813c", "question": "What is the recovery rate of acute haemorrhagic stroke in basal ganglia?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3b4ddf3e", "question": "Social Security: After an hemorrhagic stroke in a 3rd world nation, one is challenged by the SSA and local health programs; how does one continue recovery and become self-sufficient?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e6dfb814", "question": "What is the recovery process for a side stroke paralysis like?", "answers": ""}
